

Website: https://flora8984461.github.io/

Telephone: (+1) 819-775-1837 | Email: yliu538@uottawa.ca

**PROFILE** 

Excellent communication with experience working in a diverse environment. Inquisitive and continually in professional development and skill building.

Internship experience in front-end web design & development.

Advanced proficiency in a variety of UI design and web programming tools.

**SKILLS** 

programming C, Java, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Ajax, PHP, Python, MySQL

Framework JQuery, ReactJs, VueJs, Laravel, Django, Bootstrap

CMS WordPress, Drupal

Design Adobe XD, Adobe Illustrator, Axure, Balsamiq

Other tools Vagrant, Git, Docker, AWS, MS Office

**EXPERIENCE** 

09.2019- Student Web Developer, uOttawa IT Web Service, Ottawa, CA

current -Execute tests to validate the functionality of applications managed by the

team (PHPUnit).

-Help with designing and developing web applications (Drupal, PHP,

MySQL).

09.2019- Webmaster, IEEE SPAC 2020, Ottawa, CA

current -Build the website for IEEE SPAC 2020, including front-end UI design

(HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, etc.) and implementing back-end function

(Python, Django).

05.2019- Front-End Web Developer Intern, CIA School, Ottawa, CA

08.2019 -Used Adobe suits to make mockups and prototype the websites.

-Used web programming (HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, etc.) to develop

websites and improved user experience.

-Developed web applications for online study system used by teachers and

students and fulfilled interaction between backend and frontend (Ajax,

Python, Django, MySQL, etc.).

01.2019- Website Manager (Volunteer), RCEN, Ottawa, CA

04.2019 -Redesigned the website for RCEN, making it updated and more user-

friendly (PHP, Drupal, JQuery).

01.2019-	Teaching Assistant & Corrector, University of Ottawa, CA
Current	ITI1121 - Introduction to Computing II: Java programming, and experienced QA test tools such as JUnit.
	GNG1106 – Fundamentals of Engineering Computation: C programming
06.2019-	Customer Experience Representative, Chapters Indigo, CA
09.2019	-Support the daily operations of the store and use merchandising standards to create a visually appealing, stimulating store.
	-Handle customer interactions, giving detailed, personalized, friendly & polite service to ensure customer.
EXTRA ACTI	VITY
09.2019- current	Professional Development Club Founder & Event Manager, University of Ottawa, CA
	-Develop strong industry networks and relationships among students and professors.
	-Offer advice and support to students in technical professional skills development.

	-Offer advice and support to students in technical professional skills development.
09.2019- current	System Science Graduate Student Association Founder & Secretary, University of Ottawa, CA  -Organize events, maintain the website and help make decisions to support students with better experience.  -Be the bridge of communication between students and the department.
03.2019-	Member of Engineering Faculty Council, University of Ottawa, CA
current	-Represent students in system science to participate in faculty meetings.
	-Help with council decisions and coordinate with students.
EDUCATION	
09.2018-	Master of System Science - Department of Computer Science & Electrical
current	Engineering, University of Ottawa, CA
	Courses include Computer Science, Electrical & Computer Engineering, Ebusiness Technology, Mathematics, Economics and Management.
09.2014- 06.2018	Bachelor of Engineering, Hubei University, CN
	Courses included Mathematics, Programming, engineering, etc.